You practice hard every day.
I'm sorry, Gintarou-sama. Did I wake you?
Don't worry about it.
Where's the stupid kid?
She's still asleep.
Satoru-kun, breakfast is ready!
O-Okay.
You already finished cleaning?
Did Makoto sleep in again?
Sorry about that.
It's okay. I happened to wake up early this morning.
You're letting me stay here, so it's the least I can do.
That's not right, though.
I did all the cleaning back home.
Perhaps, but you have
kendo practice and studying to do,
so you probably don't get to bed until late.
Are you getting enough sleep?
I've always been a light sleeper, so it's okay.
I'm very impressed, though.
You practice at school and train at home every day.
Makoto told me that you're close to being a starter.
Oh, I don't know yet.
I don't know much about kendo,
but I hope you're chosen as a starter.
Thank you.
I'll be sure to go cheer for you.
Oh, we need to start preparing
for the summer purification ceremony.
I can skip practice for that and the day before, then.
Wait, that won't be necessary.
You have the chance to become a starter.
Makoto and I should be able to manage on our own again.
I've never participated in a
purification ceremony before.
It's possible that I'll only get in your way, but...
I see.
Then maybe I'll ask you to help.
You can bring your friends.
Makoto's planning on inviting hers.
Friends...
Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iu kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
It Really Doesn't Matter
Kendo Hall
I guess I'm too early.
The door's unlocked?
Is someone else here?
It's the captain.
That sucks.
'Sup!
Mornin'!
I suppose I'll have to let you go.
I'm sorry.
Well, I know you're in a unique situation.
Everyone should practice on their own.
I'll be back later.
Yes, sir!
You're good, but that doesn't mean
you get to skip practice all the time.
I don't care if you have family issues or whatever.
You're screwing over the people
who are trying to take this seriously.
Then I'll quit.
Is that what you want?
What? Now you're mad?
It's not like you guys will get to be starters if I quit.
Bastard!
Okay, okay. That's enough.
Captain!
Seriously.
If you're gonna fight, put your helmets on.
Come on.
U-Uh, well...
This isn't...
What's wrong?
Cowards.
Okay, Kamio.
Up for a bout?
Damn, he's huge.
But that's not all there is to him, huh?
He's definitely good.
That was tough.
You're really good.
Liar. He was wailing on me the whole time.
I always have trouble with people smaller than me.
Did he have to bring up my size?
It's not like I enjoy fighting people bigger than me.
Hey, Prince.
Huh? What's that about?
What? Isn't that what they call you?
Who calls me that?
They do.
It's the Prince!
Wow, he's so small!
Oh, he's with Kinu-chan!
You can really see the difference!
Kinu-chan!
I can think of a few better nicknames than "Prince," though,
since you're a kendo star.
They were calling you Kinu-chan.
That's an odd nickname for someone so big.
Isn't it cute?
This guy is hard to deal with.
My family owns a tofu shop.
My last name is Kinugawa.
You know, like the kind of tofu?
Oh, I see.
I left my hand exposed,
but you kept aiming for my face.
N-Not really...
I like it!
You don't like to lose, huh?
Hey! Stop it!
Your bangs are too long,
and your face is a little pale.
Are you getting enough to eat?
I am, thank you!
What is it now?!
Gotta check for blisters.
I'm fine!
I came early today because I had less to do at home than usual.
Are you always here so early?
Did you think I didn't notice you?
I also had less to do at home than usual. That's all.
Right, you're living at a shrine right now?
Sorry, I heard from the coach.
It's part of being captain.
You miss practice because
you're helping out at home?
I'm done with kendo.
I'm not particularly interested in becoming a starter.
If the other members are unhappy, I'll quit.
It's not like I have to be in a club to practice kendo.
You need to fix that attitude of yours.
It's especially bad when you have this much talent.
I know!
Prince, are you free after practice?
No, I'm not.
And stop calling me Prince.
I just said I wasn't free!
And what about our gear?!
It'll be okay if we leave it at school for a day.
Okay! Let's go, Satoru!
Where are we going?
To have fun!
Wait, Senpai!
Look at this, Satoru!
What do you think?
So close!
Makocchi, open wide!
Ikegami-san, that's bad manners.
What? But it's so much more comfortable.
Oh, I heard that Saki-chan is working.
Yep, Sakicchi is saving up money
so she can train to work in daycare.
Oh, my.
Daycare? That's perfect for her!
Wow, Saki-chan's taking control of her life.
Planning for the future, huh?
Do you know what you want to do, Yumi-chan?
I'm okay with any job where I can work with animals.
So I've been thinking about becoming a groomer.
I see.
Funabashi-san, are you...
I'm going to college.
I'll probably choose an all-girls' school.
Oh...
Saeki will be taking over the shrine, right?
And Ashihara will work at her family's inn.
What? I'm not going to take over the inn.
My big brother's got that taken care of.
Oh, really?
I love to eat, so I'm thinking about
becoming a chef or a nutritionist.
That's great. You know just what you want to do.
Don't you know what you want to do?
Huh?
I know that I want to keep our tradition alive,
but I'm not sure what exactly that means.
Why don't you work as a shrine maiden then?
That's what I wanted to do when I was little,
but our shrine isn't big enough
for a full-time shrine maiden.
Then you can become a bride.
What?!
Except that Yumippe will probably
be the first one to get married.
What? No way!
That'd make me a housewife.
I'll be so busy taking care of my husband
and kids that I'll be old before I know it!
I don't even wanna think about that!
You're only looking at the bad things, Ikegami-san.
Are you sure about that?
Anyway, this topic scares me, so can we move on?
Let's.
Ooh, look at this!
They're offering a limited-time, extra-large parfait!
It's so big.
Should I try it?
You'll upset your stomach again.
It'll be okay!
Wow, everyone's been thinking
about what they want to do in the future.
What do I want to do?
Silver  Fox
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
I'm home!
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Welcome back, Taisuke.
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
Oh, is this your friend?
He's a new club member.
Good evening.
Oh, this is unusual.
It's been a while since the
last time Sei-chan was here.
Yeah, he's been busy.
Homemade Tofu
Kinu
chan
He really does live in a tofu shop.
Nii-chan!
Welcome home!
I'm back!
Oh, you're home?
I'm back, Dad.
U-Uh, I need to get going.
Oh, we're about to have dinner.
Why don't you join us?
Stay for dinner.
Yeah, you should!
Stay for dinner!
Right?
What am I doing here?
How is it?
Oh, it's good.
There's plenty more.
He said it's good, Nii-chan!
That crap doesn't taste good, silly.
You should eat this instead.
Sorry, that's the tofu I made.
Nii-chan always screws up.
He practices every day, but he still hasn't improved.
That's harsh.
I'm doing the best I can!
Man, stop making fun of your brother!
Look, Nii-chan! A kitty!
Don't get too close to the river!
Kitty!
Uh...
This is far enough.
Sorry for dragging you around with me today.
It's okay. Though it was a bit annoying.
Thought you might say that.
Was this some kind of punishment?
Huh?
For causing trouble with the club.
What? I just wanted to hang out.
You don't like arcades?
Not really, no.
Ditto.
But I don't mind going to one every now and then.
What about...
kendo?
Does it look like I hate kendo?
No.
It looks like you love it a lot.
You have more blisters than everyone else,
and you use older gear that's been well maintained.
I'd be shocked if you told me that you hated kendo.
Most of the time, you look like you don't care about anything,
but when it comes to kendo,
you get upset about every little thing.
And when faced with a bigger opponent,
you aim for the face instead of backing down.
It's more fun to battle it out
in a kendo match than at an arcade.
If you give up now, you won't have as much fun.
But kendo isn't my top priority.
I care most about helping out at home.
Eventually, I plan to become a priest.
I've decided to quit kendo after high school.
I still care about it, though.
When you think about it,
making tofu's just about grinding
soybeans into paste and letting it sit.
But make one mistake and it turns out all wrong.
That's why I'm having trouble.
But nobody said that I have to quit kendo right now,
and I'm having fun doing both.
Kitty! Come here!
You're able to do both right now.
Why stop?
I used kendo to achieve my main goal,
so I think I'm done.
Why does that matter?
Kendo can come second while you focus on your top priority.
You're free to do everything you love.
Be greedy!
Placing things second...
I see.
Nii-chan!
You're gonna get it now!
Uh, I'm sorry about acting like a brat today.
Oh? What's this?
And thank you for this.
That'll be your excuse.
Make sure you use it correctly, you bad boy.
And whose fault is it that I'm out this late?
Drop by again, and I'll let you try
some tofu that I haven't screwed up.
I can't wait.
Satoru isn't home yet!
It's already nine!
Satoru! Where are you, Satoru?!
Calm down, Haru-chan.
Oh, he's back!
Satoru!
Is Satoru-kun back?
You were out rather late.
Uh, I was hanging out
with someone from the kendo club.
I should have called.
That's not good enough.
You made everyone worry.
What should you say?
Uh...
I-I'm sorry.
Good.
Next time, call and let us know if you're going to be late.
Hey, what's wrong?
Why are you so quiet?
I'm done.
It's not my place to say anything.
What? Tofu from Kinu-chan?!
They gave me some to bring home.
Oh, their tofu is really good!
Is the store that famous?
Sorry about today, Haru.
I wasn't worried about you.
It's been a long day.
Satoru?
Satoru-kun, are you going to take a bath?
Satoru-kun?
Huh? Haru-chan?
Oh. 'Sup, Captain?
Kamio!
Come on, guys.
Hey!
Just you wait.
While you're busy skipping practice,
I'll get strong enough to beat you,
so you better not quit 'til then!
Fine by me.
That is, if you can.
You really piss me off!
That hurts!
Hey, Taisuke!
Oh, Seishirou.
What are you doing here?
How dare you ignore my presence?
D-Don't tell me that you're...
Kamio Satoru?!
I hear that the girls have nicknamed you "Prince."
No matter.
For I am King!
Oh, this is the student council president.
Have you seen him around?
He's got good grades, but he's pretty dense.
That's why I'm his only friend.
Hold on!
When did you and I become friends?!
We've just been schoolmates since grade school! That's it!
Yeah, yeah.
My mom said to invite you over.
Every time I go, I have to eat the tofu you screwed up!
Oh, Satoru.
You won't be at practice next Friday or Saturday, right? Something happening at the shrine?
The summer purification ceremony.
Summer?
There are large festivals twice a year to cleanse off
everything that's accumulated over the past six months.
If you're interested...
Oh, you have practice.
Wait, hold on.
I think this event is very relevant for the kendo club.
We'll have a better chance of winning after being cleansed.
Are you a believer?
Wait!
Is that the event that Hiwako said she would be attending?!
Hi— Yeah...
W-Will Hiwako dress up like a shrine maiden?!
Probably.
Wait, but it's a shrine...
A shrine...
When we were in grade school,
we were chased around a shrine
by a ghostly bird wearing a kimono.
Stop!
He was traumatized by the experience.
Don't talk about it!
We were just kids.
There aren't any ghosts.
I-I'm not scared!
I just don't like talking about stuff that isn't real!
A ghostly bird?
Was that a herald?
D-Did you just laugh at me?!
No, I believe your story.
I can see them too.
Goodbye.
He laughed at me!
It's your fault!
Why don't you say something?!
You're ruining my image!
Hey! Are you listening?!
Did something good happen, Satoru?
Probably. He's practicing even harder now.
What would you know?!
What?
No, nothing happened.
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky
Preview
Silver  Fox
Hello. This is Satoru.
The summer purification takes place in June,
while the New Year's purification takes place in December.
Next time: "Makoto's Future."
Makoto's Future
May fortune be with you, hopefully.